Guide to the Robert Noyce Papers
Department of Special Collections
Robert Noyce papers
ca. 1948-1990
M1490
Noyce, Robert N., 1927-
11 linear ft. (19 manuscript boxes and 3 oversize boxes)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Collection contains documents, photographs, videotape, and audio tape (reel to reel).
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use. Requests for electronic media (audio and video tape, disks, etc.) will require a review before patron use; please refer to http://www-sul.stanford.edu/depts/spc/emedia/access.html for complete policy statement.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Noyce Foundation, 2005. Accession 2005-244.
Biography / Administrative History
Robert Noyce was a Silicon Valley pioneer who participated in the invention of the microchip. He was part of the first successful semiconductor corporation, Fairchild Semiconductor, and went on to be one of the founders of Intel. After his death in 1990, the Noyce Foundation was named by his estate.
Scope and Content of Collection
Many personal materials, including family history, and material from childhood and academic career. Also included are documents and materials from Noyce's work at Shockley Semiconductor, Fairchild Semiconductor, Intel, and the Semiconductor Industry Association. Also includes 24 video tapes, 1 reel to reel tape, and numerous newsclippings.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Fairchild Camera and Instrument Corporation; Intel Corporation; Microelectronics--History; Science--History; Semiconductors; Microelectronics Industry--California--Santa Clara County
Container List
- Series 1: Personal History
  - Subseries 1.01: Family
    - Childhood (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Don Noyce (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "From Candles to Computers: A Life of Ralph Brewster Noyce," by Donald S. Noyce (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Gay + Dotey Noyce, Bob + Phyllis White (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Harriet Noyce (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Noyce Chapel Dedication1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Noyce Family Tree (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Prairie Preacher Prairie Farmer: A Biography of George Thomas Noyce" by Donald S. Noyce (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ralph Noyce Memorial, audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Robert Norton Noyce '49 (1927-1990): Innovation and Entrepreneurialism" by Adam Noyce2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Robert Noyce's Birth Announcement (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Very Old Ancestors" by Donald S. Noyce (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Manor House Agricultural Centre and MIT RLE Currents (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 1.02: Education
    - College Letters (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Doctoral Diploma - Doctor of Philosophy in the field of Physics "Photoelectric Investigatin of Surface Stateson Insulators" - Massachusetts Institute of TechnologySeptember 23, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Grinnel College - Robert Noyce Science Center Dedication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Grinnell College - Berkeley - T.A. application SF - actuarial application (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Grinnell College - Board Service (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Grinnell College - Class of 1949 Classletters1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Grinnell College - Commencement (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Grinnell College - Extra Curriculars (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Grinnell College - Friars' Club (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Grinnell College - Grant Gale (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Grinnell College - June 1989 Speech1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Grinnell College - Letters from Family (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Grinnell College - Letters Home (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Grinnell College - Memorial Service for Robert Noyce, Grinnell CollegeSeptember 4, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Grinnell College - mid - 1980's (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Grinnell College - Misc Articles (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Grinnell College - Pig Incident + Aftermath (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Grinnell College - RNN Family Correspondence 1945--1953, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Grinnell College - Tuition Receipts Report Cards (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Grinnell College - Undergraduate Diploma B.A. Mathematics1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - High School (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Archives- Collection Guides (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Articles (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Dissertation1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Letters and Articles (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Letters Home (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Physics Department Education File (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Summer at Miami University (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Yearbook: Grinnellian, 19451945 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 1.03: Awards
    - American Association of Engineering Societies1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Congratulations - Draper Award1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Draper Award1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Electronics - The First 50 Years1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Exploratorium1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Faraday Medal1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fullbright1951 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - IEEE Award1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Industrial Research Institute1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Junior Achievement Laureate1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Misc. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - National Inventors Hall of Fame1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - National Medal of Science (President Carter)1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - National Medal of Technology1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - (Prize for I.C. Noyce + Kilby) Franklin Ins/Ballatine 1966 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - WEMA Award1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Wescon Talk1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 1.04: Planners
    - Address Book (1)1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Address Books (4) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Executive Planner 19611961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Executive Planner 19621962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Executive Planner 19651965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Executive Planner 19681968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Executive Planner 19691968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Executive Planner 19711971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Executive Planner 19721972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Executive Planner 19751975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Executive Planner 19841984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Executive Planner 19851985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Executive Planner 19861986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Executive Planner 19881988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Executive Planner 19891989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Pilots Log1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 1.05: Notebooks
    - Record Book1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Record Book (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 1.06: Patents
    - Application of Robert N. Noyce for Field Effect TransistorJanuary 2, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Application of Robert N. Noyce for Field Effect TransistorSeptember 20, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Application of Robert N. Noyce for Semiconductive DeviceFebruary 20, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Application of Robert N. Noyce for Semiconductive Device (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Application of Robert N. Noyce for Transistor Structure and MethodMarch 20, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Application of Robert N. Noyce for Transistor Structure and MethodApril 11, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Lippincott & Ralls File - D-885 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lippincott & Ralls File - D-9241959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Patentes - Fairchild Semiconductor (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Patents Misc (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Unnamed Patents - Noyce (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Damaged Originals Removed from Patent Files (replaced with copies in the original location) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Shockley, Noyce Application for Transistor Structure and MethodApril 11, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Revolutionary Ideas - Patents & Progress in America (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 1.07: Biographical and Promotional
    - American Heritage of Invention and TechnologyWinter 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bios (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Electronic DesignJune 28, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - FortuneMarch 13, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - National JournalMay 26, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Press1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Press 1980 - 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Press - National Geographic, Business Week1982, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Robert N. Noyce 1927-1990, obituary (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Probably Won't Use Clippings (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 1.08: Noyce Foundation
    - Madrigal Singers December 2, 1958, 78 rpm record (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - My Hobby - Handicraft (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 2003 Items2003 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Foundation Biographical Primary Sources (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Foundation Biographical Primary Sources (property of Ann Bowers) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Noyce Artifacts (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Noyce's Legacy1991 - 2004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Passports (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Photos and Photocopies (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - RNN -Doodles! (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - RNN Flying (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Corporations and Organizations
  - Subseries 2.01: Philco
    - Philco - Articles and Letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Philco - Background Research (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Philco - Conferences RNN attended (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Philco - Draft (conscription)1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Philco - Inactive Agreements and Ford (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Philco - Notebook, Device Conference1955 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Philco - Philco (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2.02: Schockley
    - Early Notebooks (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Shockley RNN (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 2.03: Fairchild Semiconductor
    - Fairchild Camera and Instrument Corporation Acquisition of Fairchild Semiconductor Corporation - Stock Split1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1960's Clippings1960's (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - 1980's1980's (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Annual Reports / Shareholder Reports (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Fairchild Launch (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Leadwire, vol. 1 (missing nos. 1-4, 7-12) FCI Views vol. 9, no. 7 1959, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Leadwire, vol. 2 1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Leadwire, vol. 3 (missing vol. 8)1961 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Leadwire, vol. 4 1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Leadwire, vol. 5 1963 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Leadwire, vol. 6 (missing no. 9)1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Leadwire, vol. 7 1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Leadwire, vol. 8 1966 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Misc. 1950's and 1960's1950-1960 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Misc. Fairchild (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Noyce, R. N. - Fairchild Semiconductor Contract1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Noyce, R. N. - Stock Options (Optional Agreements and Exercise)1967 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Old Items Found1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Personal (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Plant Memoires (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Resignation Letter1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission Questionnaires1968 - 1967 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 2.04: Intel
    - 25th Anniversary Publication1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Convertible Debitures1968 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - S-8 Registration Statement Employee Stock Option Plan StockNovember 18, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1969 Financing1969 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Andygrams1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Articles1970 - 1990 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - By-Laws and Incorporation Papers1968 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Clippings (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Crush1978 - 1979 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Esquire Magazine "50 Who Made the Difference"1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Humor (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Intel (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Intel Start1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Public Offering (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - National JournalMay 26, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Pillsbury1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - RNN Expense Reoprts1983 - 1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - RNN post - 19751975 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Trip to China and Hong Kong1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - V.P. Bush Tour of Intel1988 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - 35th Anniversary Publication2003 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook1990 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 2.05: Sematech
    - Scrapbook (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Congratulations Letters (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - DedicationNovember 15, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Interview1996 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Press (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Press Packet (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 2.06: Noyce Foundation
    - Personal Correspondence1990 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Personal Correspondence1981 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Personal Correspondence1977 - 1978 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Personal (RNN)1980 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Personality (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - R. N. Noyce - Personal1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - R. N. - Personal1982 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Bob - Outgoing Correspondence1986 - 1989 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Kidder Transactions (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Misc. Startups (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Mystery Clippings (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Noyce Articles by Himafter 1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Obituaries1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Political Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Press Used by RNN (not about him) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - R. Noyce Chron1984 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - RNN Current NewsDecember 1990 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - RNN - Foreign Press (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - RNN Intel Speechearly 1980 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - RNN - Inventions (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - RNN on Ethernet (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Speech MIT Innovation Symposium1976 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - The Noyce Foundation 2003 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Unionization (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 2.07: Committees
    - Donald Noyce Prize Berkeley1987 - 1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Memberships (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - National Academy of Sciences President's Circle1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - National Science Foundation1985 - 1990 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - UC Board of Regents1982 - 1988 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 2.08: Semiconductor Industry Association
    - Diplomacy (SV Ambassador)1980's (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Government Testimony (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - RNN on Japanese Competition (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Semiconductor Industry Association (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Series 3: Photos
  - Oversized (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ann Bowers (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Intel (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Slides and Negatives (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Childhood1926- 1928, 1947 - 1950 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Flies the RF-4CSeptember 7, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Series 4: Media
  - Subseries 4.01: VHS
    - KTEH 54 Silicon Valley Premiere Program (Box 3)
    - Junior Achievement The Best of Living Legends from Nation's Business TodayDecember 1, 1998 (Box 3)
    - OPP Applied MaterialsJanuary 17, 1986 (Box 3)
    - National Business Hall of Fame1989 (Box 14)
    - A. Bowers AnnouncementSeptember 28, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Noyce Memorial Service1990 (Box 14)
    - National Business Hall of Fame Modules1989 (Box 14)
    - Tribute to Robert Noyce from The Osgood Files and Photo Album (Box 15)
    - ABC World News Tonight w/ Peter Jennings Featuring R. N. Noyce Person of the WeekFebruary 23, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Bob Noyce Memorial CelebrationJune 9, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Draper Prize Dinner (2 copies)February 20, 1990 (Box 16)
    - A World of Ideas w/ Bill Moyers Inventing the Future w/ Robert Lucky Part 1 (Box 16)
    - Intel 25th Anniversary of the MicroprocessorDecember 31, 1996 (Box 16)
    - 1990 Review CBS, KTBC-TVDecember, 1990 (Box 16)
    - HP Junior Achievement National Business Leadership ConferenceApril 14, 1988 (Box 16)
    - Sematech, Inc. Robert N. Noyce Memorial Celebration June 9, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Living Legends: An Interview with Robert Noyce Profiles from the National Business Hall of Fame (Box 17)
    - Junior Achievement, Inc. "1989 NBLC Highlights"1989 (Box 17)
    - Robert Noyce ABC NewsFebruary, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Malone #211 Interview w/ Robert NoyceApril 13, 1989 (Box 17)
    - Junior Achievement, Inc. 1989 National Business Leadership Conference President George Bush Keynote SpeechApril 13, 1989 (Box 17)
    - RNN - Tomorrow Today - Shuttle Launch (Box 17)
    - Intel Presidential Ceremony Honoring the 1979 Medal of Science Awards White House CeremonyJanuary 14, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Intel Telecom '95 Keynote Address by Dr. Andrew S. Grove Geneva, SwitzerlandOctober 3, 1995 (Box 17)
    - KNTV Business Hall of FameApril 1990 (Box 17)
    - The Distinguised Lecturer Series Presents: Robert Noyce, Sematech: America Unique Tech.February 23, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Subseries 4.02: Betacam
    - Noyce Broadcast Transfers Roll 1 (Box 3)
    - Noyce Broadcast Transfers Roll 2 (Box 3)
    - Noyce - Sematech PR Roll (Box 15)
    - Noyce - Sematech PR Roll - Bad Audio (Box 15)
    - Tape 1 InsideJune 18, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Tape 3 InsideJune 18, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Tape 2 InsideJune 18, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Noyce Exterior ClarenceJune 18, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Noyce Remembers ClarenceJune 18, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Noyce Memorial B-RollJune 18, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Robert Noyce: "The Man Behind the Microchip" Visuals from Intel Museum Exhibit Text excerpts from biography by Leslie Berlin2005 (Box 15)
    - IEEE Awards Reception May 22, 1978 (Box 17)
    - Intel Remeberance Tape 1June 18, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Intel Remeberance Tape 2June 18, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Intel Remeberance Tape 3June 18, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Noyce - FSP 522 Touchstone Interview (Box 18)
    - Noyce - FSP 522 Graphics X'fer (Box 18)
    - Eclipse FS/Intel IMC Transfer Reel 130June 14, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Eclipse FS/Intel IMC Transfer Reel 120June 14, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Eclipse FS/Intel IMC Transfer Reel 100June 13, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Ch 11 San Jose February 1990 (Box 18)
    - Eclipse FS/Intel IMC Transfer Reel 111June 13, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Noyce - FSP 522 X-Fer Fm 3/4 CM 11 (Box 19)
    - Rememberance of a Life Well LivedJune 17, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Signature: R. N. NoyceJune 17, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Touchstone R. Noyce (Box 19)
  - Subseries 4.04: Audio Reels
    - Robert Noyce MemorialJune 18, 1990, audio reel (Box 20)
    - KCBS Sematech Charles Osgood "Noyce" February 20, 1990, master reel and edited audio cassette (Box 19)
  - Subseries 4.05: DVDs
    - Junior Achievement The Best of Living LegendsDecember 1, 1988 (Box 19)
    - Mike Malone Interview w/ Robert NoyceApril 13, 1989 (Box 19)
    - Junior Achievement, Inc. '989 National Business President George Bush Keynote Speech1989 (Box 19)
    - Living Legends Interview w/ Robert Noyce1989 (Box 19)
    - Person of the Week Robert Noyce ABC NewsFebruary 1990 (Box 19)
    - ABC World News w/ Peter Jennings Person of the Week R. N. NoyceFebruary 23, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Silicon Valley (Box 19)
    - Robert Noyce Memorial Intel (Box 19)
    - Draper Prize DinnerFebruary 20, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Distinguished Lecturer Series: Robert Noyce February 23, 1989 (Box 19)
    - A. Bowers AnnouncementSeptember 28, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Business Hall of FameApril, 1990 (Box 19)
    - R. N. N. Signature (Box 19)
    - Robert Noyce Memorial A. (Box 19)
    - Rememberance of a Life Well Lived B. (Box 19)
    - Tribute to Robert Noyce E. (Box 19)
    - Draper Award (Box 19)